Guide to the John G. Magee Family Papers
Magee Family (John G.) Papers
Yale Divinity Library
John G. Magee Family Papers
1870 2014
RG 242
Yale Divinity Library
11 Linear Feet
25 boxes, 2 Oversize
This collection includes correspondence, writings, photographs, films, and other documentation of the life and work of John Gillespie Magee, his son John Gillespie Magee, Jr. and other family members. The Rev. John G. Magee (1884-1953), a graduate of Yale University, served as a missionary to China under the Episcopal Church for twenty-eight years. John G. Magee witnessed the Japanese invasion of Nanking (Nanjing) in December of 1937 and the subsequent Nanking Massacre. At great risk to his own well-being and safety, Magee filmed and photographed atrocities perpetrated by the Japanese soldiers against the citizens of Nanking, He was later able to smuggle these films out of Nanking, providing evidence and witness to the war crimes that had taken place. This collection also includes the papers of John G. Magee, Jr. (1922-1941), eldest son of John G. and Faith Magee. John G. Magee, Jr. wrote the well-known poem "High Flight" prior to his death at the age of nineteen while on active service in the Royal Canadian Air Force during World War II. The papers regarding John G. Magee, Jr. document his life through his writings, photographs, and correspondence.
Magee, John Gillespie, 1884-1953
Magee, John, 1922-1941
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of David B. Magee and F. Hugh Magee, 2012; gift of John G. Magee III, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
John Gillespie Magee, Sr. was born in Pittsburgh, PA on October 10, 1884 to a notable Pittsburgh family, the son of Frederick M. and Hannah Gillespie Magee. He attended Shady Side Academy, the Hotchkiss School, graduating in 1902, and then Yale University, graduating in 1906. At Yale, Magee was a member of the Freshman Religious Committee (1902), Sophomore Class deacon (1903), and Vice President of Dwight Hall, the center for religious activity at Yale during his final year. He was a co-founder, with William Whiting Borden, of the Yale Hope Mission in 1907. From 1908 to 1910 Magee served as General Secretary of Dwight Hall. He spent the summer of 1909 as a missionary among the Winnebago Indians in Nebraska under the sponsorship of the Dutch Reformed Church. After receiving his B.D. from the Episcopal Theological School in Cambridge, Massachusetts in 1911, he spent the fall of 1911 visiting colleges on behalf of the Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions.
Magee was ordained as a minister of the Episcopal Church and appointed to be a missionary in China in 1912, stationed in Nanking [Nanjing]. While in China he met his wife, Faith Emmeline Backhouse, an English missionary serving under the Church Missionary Society. They were married in July 1921 and subsequently raised four sons: John, David, Christopher, and Hugh. When Japanese soldiers invaded Nanking in December 1937, Magee remained in Nanking as a member of the International Safety Zone Committee, which arranged with the Japanese for a section of the city not to be destroyed. As the Japanese soldiers perpetrated atrocities against the people of Nanking, John G. Magee worked tirelessly to save and protect the people he could. During this time he risked his own life to film and document the war crimes carried out by the Japanese soldiers. In 1938, he was able to smuggle these films out of China providing evidence of the Nanking Massacre. Upon his return to the United States in 1940, John G. Magee became the Curate of St. John's Church in Washington, DC, leaving in 1945 to become the chaplain to Episcopal students at Yale University from 1946 to 1953. Magee was serving as Assistant Rector of Calvary Episcopal Church in Pittsburgh, PA when he died following a heart attack in September, 1953.
Biographical / Historical
John Gillespie Magee, Jr., eldest son of John and Faith Magee, was born in China in 1922. Following his early education at the American School, Nanking (1929–1931) he went to Britain in 1931 where he continued his education first at St Clare preparatory school near Walmer, Kent (1931–1935) and then at Rugby School (1935-1939). In 1938 he won the Rugby School's Rupert Brooke Poetry Prize. Following a visit to the United States in 1939, Magee was unable to return to England due to war time conditions so he completed his education at Avon Old Farms School in Avon, Connecticut. He earned a scholarship to Yale University in July 1940 but did not enroll, choosing instead to enlist in the Royal Canadian Air Force in October of that year. He died on December 11, 1941 at age 19 in a mid-air collision while on active service in England. Magee was the author of many poems but is best known for "High Flight", which was written in 1941 shortly before his death. This poem is a favorite among aviators and one of the most celebrated poems resulting from World War II.
Scope and Contents
This collection documents the life and work of John G. Magee, John G. Magee, Jr. and other family members. Additional documentation related to John G. Magee is held by the Archives of the Episcopal Church in Austin, Texas, including letters written by Magee from Nanking in 1937.
Series I, Family Correspondence, is divided into two subseries, Extended Family and John G. and Faith B. Magee Family. The Extended Family subseries contains personal correspondence between John G. Magee and his mother and siblings. His early years in China are documented in the letters he sent to his mother. He sent many letters to his sister Mary Scaife in 1937 and 1938 documenting the conditions in Nanking during the Japanese invasion. The subseries also includes correspondence between Faith B. Magee and her parents and siblings. Faith B. Magee wrote letters to her parents documenting the courtship between her and John G. Magee and their marriage. The John G. and Faith B. Magee Family subseries includes numerous letters between John and Faith from the time of their courtship throughout their marriage. Letters documenting the conditions of Nanking leading up to the invasion by the Japanese and then the following conditions are detailed in John's letters to his wife during the time period.
Series II, General Correspondence, is comprised of general correspondence with John G. and Faith B. Magee and their children. Included in this series is a significant amount of correspondence with John G. and Faith B. Magee following John G. Magee, Jr.'s death and regarding his poem, "High Flight".
Series III, Writings, is comprised of writings by John G. Magee, Faith B. Magee, John G. Magee, Jr., and F. Hugh Magee. John G. Magee's writings include personal diaries, class notebooks, sermons and articles. The writings by Faith B. Magee include personal writings and poems. John G. Magee Jr.'s writings are comprised of the poems he wrote, including "High Flight". A sermon, article, and book by F. Hugh Magee are also included in this series.
Series IV, Nanking Documentation, contains two main components: material produced and collected by John G. Magee at the time of the Nanking Massacre, and material collected by David B. Magee through his research and work dedicated to remembering the Nanking Massacre and the important role his father played in the support of the people of Nanking. The Nanking Documentation collected by John G. Magee contains correspondence, typescripts of radio broadcasts, publications, films, and photographs arranged chronologically. The Nanking Documentation collected by David B. Magee, and by his brother F. Hugh Magee, contains correspondence, conference information, newspaper clippings, articles, photographs, and films.
Series V, Personal Items and Memorabilia, includes John G. and Faith B. Magee's date books and letter books, personal documents, biographical information, memorabilia, and Magee family newspaper clippings. The John G. Magee, Jr. subseries is comprised of personal documents, memorabilia, and collected material related to his life and his poem, "High Flight". The Henson photocopies were gathered by Ivan Docker-Henson and are comprised primarily of photocopies of material that appears elsewhere in this collection.
Series VI, Photographs and Films, contains photographs of the Magee and Backhouse families spanning the years 1870-1965. Of special interest in this series are the photographs taken of the Magee family in China, as well as photographs of Nanking and their Chinese colleagues, friends, and students. Film footage from during the Nanking Massacre as well as from other periods in Magee's life is available.
Arrangement
I. Family Correspondence, 1890-1970
II. General Correspondence, 1901-1999
III. Writings, 1906-1989
IV. Nanking Documentation, 1937-2004
V. Personal Items and Memorabilia, 1902-2011
VI. Photographs and Films, 1870-1965
Missions China; Nanking Massacre, Nanjing, Jiangsu Sheng, China, 1937; Missionaries China Jiangsu Sheng; Sino-Japanese War, 1937-1945 Atrocities; Magee, John Gillespie, 1884-1953; Magee, John, 1922-1941
- Family Correspondence, 1890 1970; Series I
  - Extended Family
    - To/from mother of John G. Magee, 1896 1941
      - John G. Magee (JGM) to his mother Hannah Gillespie Magee Neale, 1896 1898 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - JGM to his mother Hannah Gillespie Magee Neale, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - JGM to his mother Hannah Gillespie Magee Neale, 1900 1903 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - JGM to/from his mother Hannah Gillespie Magee Neale, 1905 1912 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - JGM to his mother Hannah Gillespie Magee Neale, 1919 1920 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - To/from parents of Faith Backhouse Magee
      - Letter to The Rev. Edward B. Backhouse on his marriage to Mary Anne Emmeline, from his parishioners, 1890 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Faith Backhouse from her father Edward B. Backhouse, 1900 1919 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Faith B. Magee (FBM) to/from her parents Edward B. and Mary Anne Emmeline Backhouse, 1920 1925 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - FBM and JGM from her parents Edward B. and Mary Anne Emmeline Backhouse, 1928 1939 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - JGM to his mother-in-law Mary Anne Emmeline Backhouse, 1928 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - FBM to her mother Mary Anne Emmeline Backhouse, includes correspondence regarding John G. Magee, Jr., 1940 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - FBM and JGM to/from her mother Mary Anne Emmeline Backhouse, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - FBM and JGM to/from her mother Mary Anne Emmeline Backhouse, 1943 1952 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - John G. Magee, Jr. from his grandmother Mary Anne Emmeline Backhouse (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - To/from siblings of John G. and Faith B. Magee
      - JGM from his sister Eleanor Gillespie Magee, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - JGM from his brother James McDevitt Magee, 1912; 1940 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - John G. Magee, Jr. from his uncle James McDevitt Magee, 1934; 1940 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - JGM from his sister (Margaret) Louise Magee Riedl de Ridenau (Baroness), 1906; 1912 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - JGM to/from his sister Mary Magee Scaife, 1903 1934 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - JGM to/from his sister Mary Magee Scaife, including documentation of conditions in Nanking during the Japanese invasion, 1937 1938 (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - JGM. and FBM to/from his sister Mary Magee Scaife, 1939 1955 (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - John G. Magee, Jr. to his aunt Mary Magee Scaife, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - JGM and FBM to/from her brother Edward Backhouse, 1914; 1920; 1936 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      - John G. Magee, Jr. from his uncle Edward Backhouse, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - FBM to/from her brother Ellis Backhouse, 1941 1965 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - FBM and JGM to/from her sister Ruth Backhouse, 1934 1939 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - FBM and JGM to/from her sister Ruth Backhouse, 1941 1944 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - To/from other extended family members
      - Various extended family members, including JGM cousin Margaret Larabee, 1905 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - John G. and Faith B. Magee Family
    - John G. Magee to/from Faith B. Magee
      - John Magee to Faith Magee, written from Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), Nanking, 1920 1921 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Faith B. Magee to John G. Magee, written from Beidaihe (Peitaiho), on voyage to England, from England, 1924 1925 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Faith Magee to John Magee, written on voyage to England, from England; John Magee to Faith Magee from Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), Nanking, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Faith Magee to John Magee, written from England; John Magee to Faith Magee written from Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), Nanjing (Nanking) and Zhenjiang (Chinkiang), 1932 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Faith Magee to John Magee, written from England; John Magee to Faith Magee, written from Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), Nanking, 1937 January 1937 September (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - John Magee to Faith Magee, written from Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), Nanking, 1937 October 1 1937 October 15 (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - John Magee to Faith Magee, written from Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), Nanking, 1937 October 16 1937 October 31 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - John Magee to Faith Magee, written from Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), Nanking; Faith Magee to John Magee from Pittsburgh, 1937 November 1937 December (Box 2, Folder 8)
        Scope and Contents
        Includes transcript copies made by FBM
      - JGM to FBM, written from Nanking; FBM to JGM, written from England, 1938 Jan (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - JGM to FBM, written from Nanking; FBM (and children) to JGM, written from England, 1938 Feb (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - JGM to FBM, written from Nanking; FBM to JGM, written from England, including letter from David B. Magee, 1938 Mar (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - JGM to FBM, written from Nanking; FBM to JGM, written from England, 1938 Apr (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - JGM to FBM, written from Nanking and Shanghai; FBM to JGM, written from England, 1938 May 1938 June (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - JGM to FBM, written on voyage to U.S., while on furlough, and from Shanghai and Nanking after return; FBM to JGM from England, 1939 January 1939 June (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - JGM to FBM, written from Nanking, 1939 July 1939 December (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - JGM to FBM, written from Nanking; FBM to JGM, written from England, 1940 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - JGM to/from FBM, primarily in U.S., 1942 1948 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - JGM to FBM from U.S.; FBM to JGM from England, 1951; 1953 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - JGM to/from FBM - partial letters, ca.1937, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Family correspondence to/from children
      - To/from John G. Magee, Jr., 1928 1937 (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - To/from John G. Magee, Jr.; includes school report from Rugby School, 1938 1939 (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - To/from John G. Magee, Jr., 1940 1941 (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - Christmas Card drawn by John G. Magee, Jr., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - Copies and extracts of letters re. war experience of John G. Magee, Jr., 1939 1941 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - John G. Magee, Jr. to David B. Magee, 1940 1941 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - JGM and FBM from David B. Magee, includes letters from Helen Rice Magee, 1939 1953 (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - JGM and FBM from Christopher W. Magee, includes letters from Elaine (Mimi) Magee, 1938 1953 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - JGM and FBM from F. Hugh Magee, 1952 1960 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - JGM to John G. Magee, Jr., David B. Magee, Christopher W. Magee, and F. Hugh Magee, 1936; 1939 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - JGM to Hannah G. Magee Neale, John G. Magee, Jr., David B. Magee, and Mary Magee Scaife, 1937 August 1937 October (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - F. Hugh Magee to his mother, 1968 1969 (Box 3, Folder 7a)
- General Correspondence, 1901 1999; Series II
  - Of John G. Magee
    - To JGM, including letter re. Magee's call to China from Calvary Episcopal Church, Pittsburgh, PA, 1901 1911 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Letters sent to JGM upon his departure to China, incl. from Fennell P. Turner, General Secretary of Student Volunteer Movement for Foreign Missions; letter from JGM to Dr. Drown of Episcopal Theological School describing mission work in China, 1912 1913 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - To/From JGM incl. regarding work of American Church Mission in China (Episcopal Church) and circular describing evangelistic meetings led by Sherwood Eddy (1914), 1914 1920 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - From JGM to the Editor of the Christian Century regarding the bombardment at Nanking, March 24, 1927 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - To/From JGM during the Nanking Massacre and afterward, incl. from Ernest Forster, to/from Archie T. L. Tsen, from John Wood; JGM to Bishop William Roberts, to Madame Chiang, 1937 1939 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - To/From JGM, includes letters re. future plans of the Magees, letters of condolence following the death of John G. Magee, Jr., JGM to/from T.K. Shen, letters re. film footage taken by JGM in Nanking, 1940 1944 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - To/From JGM, includes letters written while JGM served as witness at war criminal trials before International Tribunal in Tokyo (1946); letters re. resignation as missionary and taking up position as minister to Episcopal students at Yale; letter from John H.D. Rabe (1947), 1945 1949 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - To JGM, including transfer from Diocese of Connecticut to Diocese of Pittsburgh, 1952 1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - To/From JGM, incl. draft of letter to General Chiang Kai-shek, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Of Faith B. Magee
    - To FBM, incl. letter of acceptance from Church Missionary Society (1918), and from friends, 1917 1919 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - To/from Faith Magee, including from friends, announcement of her engagement to John Magee, printed letters regarding her mission work in China at Mary Vaughn High School, Hangzhou (Hangchow) and from the American Church Mission, Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), Nanking, 1920 1921 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - From Faith B. Magee, mostly printed letters from Xiaguan (Hsiakwan), 1922 1931 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - To FBM, from friends and missionary colleagues, 1932 1938 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - To FBM, from friends and missionary colleagues, 1939 1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - To/From FBM, includes letters of condolence following the death of John G. Magee, Jr., partial copy of letter from FBM to Winston Churchill, 1941 1942 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - To FBM, incl. from friends, Kanuga Association, British Embassy re. her brother who was a war prisoner, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - To FBM, incl. from friends, British Embassy, C.T. Shen, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - To/From FBM, incl. re. her son John, 1945 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - To/From FBM, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - To FBM, 1947 1952 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - To FBM, includes letters of condolence following the death of her mother and letters from Buckingham Palace regarding her visit, 1953 January 1953 June (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - To FBM, includes letters and telegrams of condolence following the death of JGM, 1953 August 1953 December (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - To FBM, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - To FBM, 1955 1959 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - To FBM, incl. from Kenneth Scott Latourette, 1960 1971 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - To/from FBM, incl. from grandchild, from "Trever", fragment (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Of John G. and Faith B. Magee
    - To/From JGM and FBM, incl. list of people from whom they received cards, 1928 1934 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      Letters in this section are addressed to/from JGM and FBM together
    - To/From JGM and FBM, incl. from missionary colleagues in China and circular letter by Magees from Washington DC (1941), 1940 1942 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - To/From JGM and FBM, 1943 1944 (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - To/From JGM and FBM, incl. from friends and China colleagues, 1945 1951 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - To JGM and FBM (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - From Ilona Rolf Sues (Polish journalist) to JGM and FBM, 1937 1944 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Regarding death of John G. Magee, Jr. and "High Flight" poem
    - Letters of condolence, re. exhibit in Library of Congress, re. "High Flight" and other poems, gift of manuscript to Yale University Library, 1941 1942 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Incl. re. offer of John G. Magee, Jr's manuscripts of "High Flight" and "Per Ardua" to Library of Congress, and from Canadian Department of National Defense re. copyright of John G. Magee, Jr's poems, 1943 1949 (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - "High Flight" Correspondence, incl. from Archibald MacLeish, 1951 1986 (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - John G. Magee to Mrs. Douglas Davidson, 1947 1949 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Of John G. Magee, Jr.
    - To John G. Magee, Jr., incl. from James C. Thomson, Jr. in Nanking, 1934 1939 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Letters of Recommendation for Enlistment in Royal Canadian Air Force, 1940 (Box 4, Folder 24)
    - To/From John G. Magee, Jr., incl. letters to publishers, letter to friends from England, 1940 1941 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Of David Backhouse Magee
    - Yale Divinity School Library regarding the China Records Project, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 26)
    - To/from David B. Magee, incl. re. "High Flight", re. John G. Magee Memorial Fund, Dwight Hall, Yale University, 1978 1986 (Box 4, Folder 27)
    - To/From David B. Magee, incl. from Jack Hasegawa re. JGM biographical information found in Yale documents, 1990 1999 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Of Christopher Walford Magee
    - Letter from Roderick I.A. Smith, RCAF 412 Squadron Mate of John G. Magee, Jr., 1987 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Of Frederick Hugh Magee
    - To/From F. Hugh Magee, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Writings, 1906 2016; Series III
  - Writings by John G. Magee
    - Personal Diary, 1906 1912 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Diaries - documenting missionary work in China, 1916 1919 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Examination, Episcopal Theological School, Jun 1909 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Class Notebook from Prayer Book with Dean Hodges, Episcopal Theological School, Cambridge, Massachusetts, 1909 1910 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - "The Family as the Dominating Idea in Chinese Civilization, Graduation Thesis. Episcopal Theological School, 1911 May 15 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Notebook containing stories recorded by John G. Magee, 1911 1912; 1950 1953 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Article - "Nanking Passing Through Troubled Days" (photocopy), ca.1927 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Talk - "Work for Lepers at...", 1927 Dec 14 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Chapter, "God and the Church" in Together, edited by Rufus Matthew Jones (New York, Nashville, Abingdon-Cokesbury Press), 1946 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Brewster Memorial Corporation at Yale: Report of the Minister to Episcopal Students, The Reverend John G. Magee, 1947 1948; 1948 1949; 1951 1952; 1952 1953 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Poetry written by John G. Magee, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Sermon: "Living for Christ Like Needles", 1919 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Sermon: "Christianity Means Fellowship," American Church Mission, Nanking, China, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Sermon: Invocation at Madeira School Graduation, 1944 Jun 5 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Sermon: Sunset Service, Isleboro, ME, 1944 Aug 27 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Sermon: "Repent and Believe," St. John's Church, Washington, DC, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Sermon: "The Flesh and the Spirit, Gal. 5:16-24 - Epistle 14th Trinity," Cavalry Episcopal Church, Pittsburgh, PA - last sermon written by John G. Magee, 1953 Sep (Box 5, Folder 16)
      This sermon was not delivered by Magee because he suffered a heart attack on that Sunday morning and was taken to the hospital.
  - Writings of Faith B. Magee
    - Incl. article re. Nanking Language School, and personal writings, 1919 1931 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - "Coronation of King George VI and Queen Elizabeth," Magazine of Holy Trinity Church, Northwood. Mdx - England, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Talk given at Kingsdown House, 1938 Mar 22 (Box 5, Folder 19)